A Guide to the Papers of Frances Hodgson Burnett 1889-1914
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of Frances Hodgson Burnett, 1889-1914
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
6817-e
This collection consists of 12 items.
Administrative Information
Access
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was purchased by the Library on March 3, 1993.
Scope and Content Information
The collection contains a letter, 1889 August 19, to Stephen Townesend asking him to visit and referring to their literary collaboration. A letter, 1900 May 24, to "Katherine" describes her miserable marriage to Townesend whom she was forced to marry and believes insane. In a letter, 1907 October 23, she regrets to Katherine Thomas that she can undertake no more work.
Remaining letters and postcards, 1914, to Mildred Johnston and a Mrs. Lincoln are chiefly brief personal notes of greeting, thanks, and sympathy.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged chronologically.
Contents List
- Frances Hodgson Burnett, Dorincourt, Bellagio, Surrey, to Stephen Townesend [1889 Aug 19], ALS, 2 p. on 1 l.
  Asking him to visit and referring to their collaboration on dramatizing some of her novels.
- Frances Hodgson Burnett, Matham Hall, Polvenden, Kent, to "Dear Katherine" (in text) 1900 May 24, ALS, 12 p. on 3 l.
  Writing a very heartfelt letter concerning her miserable marriage to Stephen Townesend and describing generally an account of what has been occurring.
- Frances Hodgson Burnett, Sands Point, Port Washington, Long Island, to Katherine Thomas, New York 1907 Oct 23, ALS, 4 p. on 1 l.
  Indicating that she would be pleased to have her visit, but regretting that she is too overwhelmed to undertake any new work if the Cosmopolitan pays her the compliment of wanting something.
- Frances Hodgson Burnett, Place de la Concorde, Paris, France, to Mildred Johnston 1914 Mar 12, ALS, 7 p. on 2 l.
  Expressing sorrow over her mother's illness; concerning her future plan to travel from Algiers to London, New York, and then Bermuda with her sister Edith; and describing some of her visit in Paris.
- Frances Hodgson Burnett, Hyde Park Hotel, Knightsbridge, London, to Mildred Johnston 1914 Apr 21, ALS, 3 p. on 1 l.
  Expressing her sympathy over the death of her mother and offering comfort.
- Frances Hodgson Burnett, Plandome Park, Plandome, Long Island, to Mildred Johnston 1914, ALS, 1 p.
  Sending her a gift from Munich.
- Frances Hodgson Burnett, [New York], to "Dear Friend," offering an amusing explanation for her tardiness in answering a letter n.y. Monday, ALS, 4 p. on 1 l.
- Frances Hodgson Burnett, The Grosvenor, [New York], to Mildred Johnston n.y. Dec, ALS, 4 p. on 1 l.
  Thanking her for the gift of the handkerchiefs and praising the Grosvenor.
- Frances Hodgson Burnett, Plandome Park, Plandome, Long Island, to Mildred Johnston n.d., ALS, 1 p.
  Returning borrowed money.
- Frances Hodgson Burnett, Alger, to Mildred Johnston n.d., APCS
  "Looking down on Algiers to the Mediterranean."
- Frances Hodgson Burnett to Mildred Johnston n.d., APCS
- Frances Hodgson Burnett, Washington, D.C., to Mrs. Lincoln n.d., ALS, 3 p. on 1 l.
  Telling her what a charming idea the "Uncut Leaves" seemed to her.